Eugeniu CARARUS

Senior software engineer

☐ Glasgow United Kingdom
+44 7479012317
⊠ cararuseugeniu@gmail.com
uk.linkedin.com/in/cararuseugeni

Summary

I'm specialising in building server-side transactional web applications and Restful web services, I mainly used traditional Java and JEE technology stack on tomcat/jetty/weblogic server by using SpringFramework, Struts MVC with Hibernate and Mule ESB.

I have 9 years of professional experience worked in various very interesting and demanding projects, mainly large scale distributed projects. I had a chance to work in big multi-threaded, concurrent, standalone application, but also I was working on greenfield projects mainly at the start of my career path.

Following trends I recently started to focus more in functional languages, I'm learning Scala and Closure, I studding different NoSQL databases mainly MongoDB and Lucen, as well I'm interested into cloud infrastructure and configuration management, I also worked on projects with different languages/frameworks like Groovy(Grails), PHP(Drupal) or GWT. I had a chance to work within great agile teams distributed across the world with high coding standards in agile environment that valued lean and mature approach, embracing continuous integration and continuous delivery, integration tests, unit tests, pair programming by doing continuous codebase refactoring, I'm targeting continuous code improvement, and new technologies implementation. In terms of team organisation my slogan is "let's build mature self managed team".

Generally I'm very focused, process oriented technical person. I like knowing how things work around me and I always look for new exciting opportunities.

Work History

Associate

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Oct 2014 - Present

JPMorgan Chase & Co. (NYSE: JPM) is a leading global financial services firm with assets of \$2.6 trillion and operations worldwide. The Firm is a leader in investment banking, financial services for consumers and small businesses, commercial banking, financial transaction processing, and asset management. A component of the Dow Jones Industrial Average, JPMorgan Chase & Co. serves millions of consumers in the United States and many of the world's most prominent corporate, institutional and government clients under its J.P. Morgan and Chase brands. Information about JPMorgan Chase & Co. is available at www.jpmorganchase.com.

Senior Software specialist in open source solution management.

Pentalog Nov 2013 - Oct 2014

Black Duck client. Offering award-winning software and consulting, our client is the partner of choice for open source software adoption, governance and management to enterprises of every size.

Open Hub project - The developed web application allows the building of a knowledge base regarding open source information, as well as analysis of software IP and open source risk profiling on software components. Overall, it enhances the open source software management through better control of existing code, improvement strategies and continuous learning.

Mission description: Developer within the back-end team. Analysis and estimation of the functional and technical evolutions. Writing the architecture and the detailed technical design. Carrying out the functional and the technical evolutions. Carrying out tests and solving bugs. Code reviewing every code change together with the team. Documenting guides and techniques.

Technology: Zookeeper 1.5.1, Solr 4.6.0, PostGreSQL 9.1, Querydsl 3.3.0, EhCache 2.6.8, Hibernate 4.2.0, Spring 3.2.7, JAVA 7

Team size: 8

Senior Software Engineer

Pentalog Apr 2013 - Nov 2013

Project Nord Net- Division of a main telecom operator established in the center of the Lille metropolis. The team is focused on providing two main types of activities: Third-Party Application Maintenance services provided in Moldova, which includes the corrective and upgrade maintenance on front-end side for several applications and on the client's backoffice applications, Team ensures design, analysis and technical research services.

Technology stack: JAVA, Spring 2.5, Spring 3.2, JPA, Hibernate 3.x, Axis 1.4, CXF 2.3, SpringSecurity 3.1, JSF, RichFaces, JUnit, DBUnit, Unitils, JBehave, MySQL 5.0.x, Maven, Dozer, JAXB, Drools, JBoss 4.x GA, jQuery, Jenkins, Apache, Redmine.

Team Size: 11

Software Development Engineer

Pentalog Apr 2011 - Apr 2013

Project ELSTER ENERGYICT: Team develops several projects concerning the design and development of energy management hardware and software solutions and services targeted towards the utilities and energy suppliers as well as to the end clients.

Technology stack: Java 1.5/1.6/1.7, Internal framework, Internal Application Server, Oracle, Apache Maven 2.2.1, JIRA, GoogleMaps, JUnit, EasyMock, PowerMock, Mockito, env virtualisation

TEAM SIZE: 15

J2EE Developer

Pentalog Sep 2010 - Mar 2011

Project for Fragrances and flavours industry: Development of a web application for managing the product transfer process in the production environment.

Technology stack: Java 1.5, Spring 2.5, Hibernate 3.3, Struts 2, Oracle 10g, WebSphere Application Server 6.1, JUnit, CSS, Apache, JSP / Servlets, Struts, LDAP, Oracle, WebSphere, JavaScript

Team size: 7

J2EE Developer

Pentalog Oct 2009 - Sep 2010

ALTADIS GROUP Strator project: The purpose of the project was to create a software solution, named Gamme6, consisting of 2 parts: - Desktop application installed on the cash register in the point of sale; - Web Strator application installed on a Strator server in an Altadis environment that will be available via Internet as a Web application.

Technology stack: JAVA, AJAX, Tomcat, JBoss, Hibernate, Spring, JavaScript, jQuery, JSF, RichFaces, JUnit, PostGreSQL, Eclipse, Maven.

Team size: 32

Software Developer

F-Line Technologies Aug 2009 - Oct 2009

PROJECT: E-Banking solution.

Mission Description: Implement security and user management module.

Technology Stack: As company is Platinum partner of Oracle key technologies used for development of application was mainly Oracle products such as OracleADF with UI written by using PrimeFaces/RichFaces, OracleBI as reporting solution, Oracle10g, WebLogic application server.

Junior Software Developer

ICS Mobiteam Jun 2007 - Aug 2009

Mission Description: Development of dating portal. Development of new features for the Dating Service and the System Administration Tool. Maintenance of the portal. In charge of providing support for the developed modules.

Technology stack: Java, Hibernate, Maven, PostgreSQL PLPG/SQL, JNDI, JDBC, JSP/Servlets, JavaScript, CSS.

Web Developer

Center of the Network and Internet Resources of the Science Mar 2007 - Jun 2007 Academy of Moldova

Responsability: Create Web site for Science Academy of Moldova www.asm.md and Center of Networks and Resources of Science Academy www.crri.md

Technology stack: PHP, MySQL, Drupal, ApacheServer, HTML, JavaScript

Education

Continuous developement and online courses

Princeton University 2015 - 2016

Master Degree in Information Technology

Technical University of Moldova 2009 - 2011

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

Technical University of Moldova. 2005 - 2009

Languages

English

Full professional proficiency

Full professional proficiency

Russian

Native

Romanian

Native

Training and continuous devlopement

May 2011: jQuery Training.

Jan 2011: Spring Training.

Jan 2013: SCM: GIT/SVN

Mar 2014: Scrum, Agile

Jun 2014: Advanced SQL optimization

Oct 2014: Clean coder

Jan 2014: Kanban

Nov 2014: Vagrant, puppet